

# About me

Hi! I'm Giacomo. I am a lead software engineer in Bremen, Germany.

Currently I lead a cloud native fullstack team. I enjoy the management and the coding part of my job likewise. I am also involved in Product Management, and in the Scrum process.

I have a bachelor degree in computer science and a PhD in mathematics. I have broad interests ranging from CAD, Machine Learning, optimization, scientific computing, 3D visualization and computational geometry, to web development, microservices and cloud computing.

I've been working on engineering software since 2012.

# **Technologies**

**©** C++ ASP.Net **ⓒ** C# CAD CAE CI/CD Databases Docker FEM **≫** Haskell **HOOPS** Communicator HOOPS Exchange Js JavaScript **∆** Linux .Net Machine Learning Optimization **Python** React & Redux Rust Scrum SQL TDD Ts TypeScript ▼Vue.JS WebAssembly

# **Experience**

### Synera GmbH Lead Software Engineer

**Jan 2020 to now** At Synera I lead the *cloud services* team. In addition to the management tasks I also develop cloud microservices using C# with ASP.Net and Rust, together with

their front ends with TypeScript and Vue.JS.

I also work on integration of *simulation* and *optimization* solvers in our C# application and on computational geometry algorithms in C++.

### Contact Software GmbH Senior software engineer

# Oct 2012 to Dec 2019

At Contact I was a developer of *PLM web applications*. I used Python for the backend and JavaScript with the React/Redux framework for the frontend.

I was the product owner of the products *3D Visualization, Variant management,* and *BOM/Virtual product.* I also managed the agile development processes for these products.

Contact Software GmbH Software engineer

Juli 2011 to Sep 2012 During my PhD at the university of Bremen I had a part time developer position at Contact. In this time I worked on the packages *KPI/metrics* and *Variant management* of the PLM software.

Universität Bremen Wis

Wissentschaftlicher Mitarbeiter

Feb 2010 to Sep 2012

During my PhD I had a part time position as a research and teaching assistant (Wissentschaftlicher Mitarbeiter) at the mathematics department. I did some research related to my PhD thesis and teached exercise classes in algebra and topology.

# Education

Universität Bremen PhD

**2010 to 2012** *Summa cum Laude.* 

I wrote my <u>PhD thesis</u> on the combinatorics and algebraic topology of toric arrangements at the mathematics department of the university of Bremen.

Università di Pisa Master degree in Mathematics

**2006 to 2009** *110 cum Laude/110.* 

Master degree in mathematics at the university of Pisa. I had a focus on abstract algebra and algebraic topology. My master thesis was about representation theory and hyperplane arrangements.

Università di Pisa Bachelor degree in Computer Science

**2002 to 2006** *110 cum Laude/110.* 

Bachelor degree in computer science at the university of Pisa. I had a focus on optimization and operational research. My bachelor thesis was about optimization methods for non differentiable convex problems.

## Skills

### Languages

ItalianNativeGermanFluentEnglishProficientDutchBasic

### Personal

**Interests** Running, Swimming, Triathlon, Gardening, Slow food.